# Nandish Shanabog C S

Accomplished Mainframe Expert, AI & ML Aspirant. digitalblood1985@gmail.com, +91-9900553755

## Professional Summary

He is currently working on ProSwitch and ProMatch products (Payments Domain), as a mainframe developer. He has around 16 years of experience in development, enhancement, and maintenance of various applications on mainframes. He has also worked on a few automation initiatives using Jenkins, Selenium and Java, and Unix Shell Scripting. He is an aspiring and research-oriented data science enthusiast and worked on a few data analysis projects in addition to mainframe development.

He is an accomplished Mainframe Professional whose career has focused on the Development / Enhancement and Maintenance of Mainframe Applications, Team Management, Database Programming, and Applications Programming on Python, COBOL, PL/I, Easytrive. He was leading a Mainframe team currently. His responsibilities include activities ranging from managing development efforts, client interactions, Coding and Testing Mainframe applications, Integration of the modules and packaging the code for shipment, handling mainframe release and deployment activities.

He holds a master's degree in computer networks, and currently he is pursuing his doctoral program (PhD) in Machine Learning & Artificial Intelligence. He is an active member of the International Association of Engineers. From past few years, he started implementing projects on Data sciences (ML & AI) to draw meaningful insights from the data to aid the management to take improvement measures, and better data driven decisions. He had automated few web-based routine work - using Selenium (with Java), which largely reduced the manual efforts.

### Skills Profile

## Technical

Operating System	IBM MVS, IBM z/OS, Linux, Windows		
Database	DB2, Oracle, MySql		
Scripting	Unix Shell Scripts, Windows Batch Scripting, REXX.		
Languages	For Machine learning - Python, NumPy, Pandas, MatPlotLib, Sci-Kit Learn, Seaborn. For Mainframes - PL/I, COBOL, Easytrive		
Tools	For ML: PyCharm, Jupyter Notebook, Spyder, Jenkins, PowerBI, Excel For Mainframes: File Aid, File Manager, Endevor, Expediter, Tivoli OPC Scheduler, Abend-Aid, Data Visualizer, DBeaver		
Other	JCL, VSAM. Selenium using Java.		

#### Functional

	Team Management.		
Management and	Playing Scrum Master Role in current project and previous		
Leadership Skills	projects.		
	Assisted my manager in most of the managerial activities.		

## Professional Experience

Products: ProSwitch & ProMatch (Payments domain) Organization: TietoEvry

Role: Mainframe Lead Duration: July 2021 - Till date

As a mainframe lead, he is responsible for the following activities:

- Ensuring smooth deliveries (Patch / Release) for clients.
- Answering the questions from the customers related to products. Co-ordinate with the product owners to seek advice and decide on the feasibility and applicability of the solutions.
- Being the first point of contact for the clients for the applications related to technical queries.
- Mainframe team management including but not limited to estimation of man hours, assessing the time efforts required for each release, prioritization of the backlog tickets (discussing with product owner and clients), management of development and testing, coding, reviewing the code, release management, conducting post go-live retrospective meetings, and supporting the clients for the applications.
- Developed and deployed an anomaly detection module for fraud check. The fraudulent transactions were screened by the mainframe application. The new ML model was created to reduce the load on the existing mainframe fraud check module by filtering out the transactions that were fed to MF fraud check modules. This reduced the load on MF fraud check modules by around 18%

#### Tech-stack:

Mainframes - COBOL, DB2, JCL, CICS (Wits), VSAM, IMS-DC.

ML - Python, Java, Unix Shell Scripting, Windows Batch, NumPy, Pandas, MatPlotLib, Seaborn, Sci-kit Learn.

Project: Nordea (Cards domain) Organization: Capgemini

Role: Senior Consultant Duration: May 2016 - July 2022

As a Senior Consultant, he is responsible for the following:

- Setting up Host Adapter server for receiving authorization request from various payment schemes and sending back the authorization responses to the authorization initiators. End-to-end setup of host adapter with firewall ports, external communications and MQ connections.
- Being part of the development team that decode the ISO-8583 messages into clear text, as part of CSI program.
- Automated many manual processes on Mainframe and Web applications, that saved time and cost to the bank.
- Implementing the CI/CD, of automation of web applications using Jenkins, Selenium and Java.
- Providing L3 support for the authorization applications on Nordea bank cards.
- Automation of SWISH payments verification initiative (POC, not developed).
- Leading the L3 teams (Local business reporting & Regulatory reporting teams).
- Handled the packaging and release management for LBR and RR teams.

#### Tech-stack:

Mainframes - IBM MQ, Mainframe - COBOL, PL/1, JCL, DB2.

For automation - Java, Selenium, Jenkins, Windows Server, Unix Shell Scripting, and Windows batch scripting.

Project: Information Resources, Inc. (IRI) Duration: Jul 2014 - May 2016

Role: Senior Consultant Organization: Harman

He worked for IRI. IRI is a market research company which provides clients with consumer, shopper, and retail market intelligence and analysis focused on the consumer-packaged goods (CPG) industry.

- As a mainframe developer, he was responsible for gathering the sales data and products data from various sources like DB2 database, mainframe VSAM file, and pre-process the data. Format the data in a specific structure that the mainframe applications could process. Feed the data to the mainframe scheduled job and monitor the jobs. Handle incidents related to mainframe batch jobs.
- Improve the batch jobs for performance, and as per the change in the data formats / structures.
- Perform minor and major change requests that includes requirements gathering, estimation of efforts, coding and unit testing, and peer reviews.

#### Tech-stack:

Mainframes - Mainframe - COBOL, PL/1, JCL, DB2 and CICS.

Project: Credit Risk Assessment, Danske Bank AB Duration: Sep 2013 - Jun 2014

Role: Associate IT Consultant Organization: Danske Bank

As an Associate IT Consultant, he was responsible for

- Working on the Incidents & Problem reports from Credit Risk Management area.
- Being part of the team, which drives customer satisfaction by maintaining stable systems and reducing operational costs, thereby empowering the IT Group.
- Maintaining and enhancing the Risk Management applications on mainframe (PL/1, COBOL, DB2 and JCL).
- Working on some critical performance tuning activities to reduce the platform cost - mostly on DB2.
- Provide quick solution for the incidents to keep the Production environment go smooth and provide the permanent fix for the problems by doing root cause analysis.

#### Tech-stack:

Mainframes - Mainframe - COBOL, PL/1, JCL, DB2 and CICS, IMS-DB and DC.

Project: AMEX Duration: Oct 2010 - Sep 2013

Role: Senior Software Engineer Organization: Mindtree Ltd

He was part of AMEX Cards team. As a Senior Software Engineer, he was responsible for:

- Providing L3 support for Cards team and provide on-call support.
- Communicating with clients & on-site coordinator to understand the requirements, decide upon the design considerations.

## Nandish Shanabog C S

- He was part of a team responsible for documenting the Impact analysis and Unit test case report.
- Implement the changes to the system in a manner that the proposed application changes are technically feasible and easy to maintain.
- Provide on-call technical support for production issues. Analyze the production logs to understand the point of crash, fix the issue / instruct the helpdesk about the appropriate actions to be taken.
- Participate in weekly status review meetings to discuss the progress of work, technical difficulties faced (if any), and dependencies from other teams.

#### Tech-stack:

Mainframes - Mainframe - COBOL, JCL, DB2, CICS and VSAM.

Project: NASCO Duration: Aug 2008 - Sep 2010

Role: System Engineer / Application Developer Organization: IBM India

NASCO is a prominent health insurance provider in US. NASCO processes health claims for about 7.4% of all Blue Cross and Blue Shield members, nearly 5.5 million, throughout the United States. As an Application Developer he was responsible for:

- Analysis and development of the Auto Approval Models for a Mainframe based application system for BCBS Michigan claim approvals.
- He was responsible for modernizing BCBS Michigan programs.
- Analyzing the existing interdependence between the subsystems and modernizing the programs to make the subsystems independent of each other.
- Provide business support to clients being a part of mainframe team.

## Tech-stack:

Mainframes - Mainframe - COBOL, JCL, DB2, PL/1 and VSAM.

# Summary of Projects

Functional Domain Name	Experience	Description
Mainframe Technology / Training	Did not worked on any project. Just got Trained on Mainframe.	Infosys (Mysore). I could not pass the training (comprehensive exam due to illness). Asked to resign.
Mainframe Technology / Healthcare	From Aug 2008 to Sep 2010	IBM (GBS) - Worked for NASCO - A health insurance provider in USA.
Mainframe / Banking - Cards.	From Oct 2010 to Sep 2013	Mindtree Limited - Amex Cards.
Mainframe / Banking - Credit Risk	From Sep 2013 June 2014	ITC Infotech India Ltd - Danske Bank - Credit Risk Management
Mainframe / Retail	From July 2014 to May 2016	Harman (Symphony Teleca Corp) - IRI Retail.
Mainframe / Banking - Products	From May 2016 to July 2021	Capgemini India (Nordea - Cards).
Mainframe / Banking - Payments	From July 2021 - till date	TietoEvry India Pvt Ltd - Payments Domain (products: ProSwitch & ProMatch).

## Nandish Shanabog C S

#### Education

Visvesvaraya Technological University, Belgaum, M. Tech, Computer Networks, 2018. Visvesvaraya Technological University, Belgaum, B. E, Computer Science and Engineering, 2008.

# Professional Organizations

International Association of Engineers (2017-present) Membership ID: 190921

## Publications & Presentations

- Published a technical paper in IEEE on 'Use of Genetic Algorithms for prediction of heart diseases' in 2018 https://ieeexplore.ieee.org/document/8256952
- Published a technical paper titled 'Prioritization of Accident Black Spots using GIS' in IJERT (ISSN: 2278-0181), Volume 9, Issue 5, May-2020.
   https://www.ijert.org/research/prioritization-of-accident-black-spots-using-gis-IJERTV9IS050465.pdf
- Presented a technical paper on 'Use of Genetic Algorithms for prediction of heart diseases' at IEEE Recent Trends on Electronics, Information & Communication Technology, IEEE RTEICT-2017, held in Bangalore.
- Presented a technical paper on 'Early prediction of heart-related diseases using Genetic Algorithms' to World Congress on Engineering and Computer Science WCECS 2018, San Francisco, USA.

## Certifications

- Certified International Payment Systems Professional (CIPSP)<sup>™</sup> by MVLCO. Issued on 09-Jan-2023, Certificate Number: 229T-854-5N1.
- Certified Scrum Product Owner® from SCRUM ALLIANCE® Certificate ID: 001322449, Valid Till 25 Feb 2024
- Course completion certificate from IIT, Bombay on Python 3.4.3.
- Scientific computing with Python certificate from freeCodeCamp.

## References

- Sairam Srinivasan,
   Senior Director, Capgemini,
   sairam.srinivasan@capgemini.com
   +919840275046
- 2. Mandar Deshpande
   Senior Manager, Capgemini
   mandar.deshpande@capgemini.com
   +918390909768